hi folks this is Matt and so we're
大家好，我是马特，所以我们
talking a little bit about social choice
谈一点社会选择
theory now and I'll introduce you to
现在讲理论，我将向您介绍
voting schemes and social choice
投票方案与社会选择
functions and in terms of the overall
功能和整体
idea what we're looking at now as we
知道我们现在在看什么
were looking at a set of setting where a
在看一组环境
society's making decisions and we've got
社会的决策，我们已经
a bunch of different individuals who
一堆不同的人
have preferences and that we want to
有偏好，我们想要
aggregate those right so we've got a set
汇总这些权利，所以我们有一套
of voters a set of people they have to
选民的一组他们必须
make decision and we want to take into
做出决定，我们要考虑
account the Preferences of the different
帐户的首选项不同
individuals so we're looking at a
个人，所以我们正在寻找
setting where we have a set of outcomes
设定我们有一套结果的地方
or a set of alternatives so something
或一组替代方案等等
we're going to choose over so it could
我们将选择，以便可以
be a political set of political
政治上的政治
candidates it could be that we're trying
候选人可能是我们正在尝试
to choose this set of new members for a
选择这组新成员
society that we're trying to decide on a
我们试图决定的社会
new tax rate for government we've got a
政府的新税率
whole series of different questions and
一系列不同的问题和
there's possible outcomes that are there
有可能的结果
and the people the voters the agents the
和人民选民代理
people in the society
社会上的人
have preferences over these outcomes so
对这些结果有偏好，所以
in this setting we're going to look at
在这种情况下，我们将要看
for now people are going to have
现在人们将拥有
preferences they'll be able to tell you
他们可以告诉您的偏好
this is my favorite outcome this is my
这是我最喜欢的结果这是我的
second favorite my third my fourth and
第二喜欢我的第三我第四
so forth and what a social choice
等等，这是什么社会选择
function is going to do is take the
功能要做的就是
preferences of the individuals and as a
个人的喜好
function of those tell us which outcome
这些功能告诉我们哪个结果
are we're going to choose so it's going
我们要选择吗
to be a mapping from profiles of
是来自以下配置文件的映射
preferences to a particular outcome and
对特定结果的偏好，以及
generally what we're going to be
通常我们将成为
interested in is sort of which ones
对什么感兴趣
which of these social choice functions
这些社会选择功能中的哪个
would we like to have now in the course
我们现在想要课程吗
we're going to eventually have to talk
我们最终将不得不谈论
about incentives because people you know
关于激励措施，因为您认识的人
in a setting where we're voting for a
在我们投票支持的环境中
bunch of candidates it might be that I
一堆候选人可能是我
actually and you ask me which one's my
其实你问我哪个是我的
favorite candidate I might not tell you
最喜欢的候选人我可能不会告诉你
truthfully which is my favorite
老实说这是我的最爱
candidate I might vote for somebody else
我可能会为其他人投票的候选人
if I think my candidate has no chance of
如果我认为我的候选人没有机会
winning the election so people might try
赢得选举，以便人们可以尝试
and manipulate the voting scheme by by
并通过以下方式操纵投票方案
changing the how they represent their
改变他们代表自己的方式
preferences they'll say okay actually I
他们会说“好吧”
would like to vote for this person not
不想为此人投票
for this other person so we'll have to
为了这个人，所以我们必须
we'll have to very carefully think about
我们必须非常仔细地考虑
how the mapping from preferences into
如何从偏好映射到
all turn
全部转
eventually is achieved but for now what
最终实现了，但是现在
we're going to do is we're just going to
我们要做的就是
look at the function itself and say hey
看一下功能本身，然后说嘿
okay if society you know there's a whole
好吧，如果社会，你知道整个
ways a set of ways in which these things
这些东西的一套方式
can be mapped and then later we'll ask
可以被映射，然后我们会问
which ones can actually be achieved or
哪些实际上可以实现，或者
how they can be achieved and so forth so
如何实现这些目标等等
given is a set of preferences or outcome
给定的是一组偏好或结果
I were sorry outcomes were alternatives
我很抱歉结果是替代方案
so that's going to be the set oh and
这样就可以了哦
people are going to have preferences
人们将有偏好
over these and we're going to represent
这些，我们将代表
these in a very simple form generally
这些通常以非常简单的形式
they're the agents are going to have
他们是代理商要拥有的
strict preferences over these things so
对这些东西有严格的偏好，所以
we'll eliminate in differences that will
我们将消除差异
make our life easier so that's going to
让我们的生活更轻松，这将
be represented by this relationship
被这种关系所代表
which is going to be generally linear
通常是线性的
orders so we'll look at situations where
下订单，因此我们将研究以下情况
people are not indifferent so they'll be
人们并不冷漠，所以他们会
having a linear order or what's known as
具有线性顺序或所谓的
a total order over the alternative so
总订单超过其他
they can tell you which is my favorite
他们可以告诉你哪个是我的最爱
which is my second-favorite and so forth
这是我的最爱，依此类推
so given a finite set I can just list
所以给定一个有限集，我可以列出
them in order and so above a linear
它们按顺序排列等等
order the set of linear orders will let
订购线性订单集将使
be denoted by L and there's going to be
用L表示
the binary relations which are total and
总和的二进制关系
transitive what does that mean that
可及的是什么意思
means if you look at any two
意味着如果你看任何两个
alternatives any two outcomes a and B
替代任何两个结果a和B
that are not equal to each other then
那彼此不相等
either a is preferred to B or B is
a优先于B或B为
preferred to a but not both so it means
首选而不是两者都选，所以这意味着
first of all I can tell you which of the
首先，我可以告诉您
two I prefer and I'm not indifferent
两个我更喜欢，我并不冷漠
okay so one part about the linear orders
好吧，关于线性订单的一部分
it's gonna be a strict ordering I'm
这将是一个严格的命令我
never going to be indifferent and for
永远不会冷漠，因为
any two alternatives I can always make a
我总是可以选择任何两种选择
comparison I can't say I don't know I'm
比较我不能说我不知道​​我是
not sure I'm not undecided all these
不确定我还不确定吗
voters are decided they can tell you
选民们决定他们可以告诉你
exactly how they rank everything and
他们到底如何排名
preferences are going to be strict
偏好将严格
they're also going to be transitive so
他们也将是可传递的，所以
if I like a better than B and be better
如果我比B更喜欢一个更好的
than C then I better like a better than
比C好，我比
C okay so we've got a nice transitive
好的，我们有一个不错的传递
ordering that's going to be a linear
排序将是线性的
linear order as total and transitive
线性顺序为整体和传递
sometimes we'll also be working with non
有时我们也会与非
strict preferences so it could be that
严格的偏好，所以可能是
someone's indifferent so then we'll
某人无动于衷，那么我们将
allow for transitivity and completeness
允许传递性和完整性
you can make a comparison
你可以做一个比较
between a and B so a could be weakly
在a和B之间，因此a可能很弱
preferred to be B weakly preferred to a
优先于B弱于a
and you could have both relationships
你们可能有两种关系
holding at the same time which means
同时举行意味着
you're actually indifferent so sometimes
你实际上很冷漠所以有时候
it'll be better to work with non strict
最好与非严格的人一起工作
relationships and in fact when we're
关系，事实上，当我们
thinking about how society decides on a
思考社会如何决定
relationship it might mean it might be
关系可能意味着它可能是
that you know everybody in the society
你认识社会上的每个人
has a strict ranking but then society as
有严格的排名，但社会
a whole ends up with a weak ordering so
整个结果以弱的顺序结束
so we'll allow for from non strict
所以我们会允许非严格
preferences as well okay so those are
偏好设置还可以，所以
going to be preferences those are the
将成为偏好的是
objects that we're going to assume
我们要假设的对象
people have and then based on those we
人们拥有的，然后基于我们
try and make a choice for the society
尝试为社会做出选择
okay so the formal model then in terms
好了，那么正式模型
of the way that will work through social
通过社交运作的方式
choice functions we've got a set of
选择函数，我们有一组
individuals finite set of individuals
个人有限的个人集
finite set of outcomes oh and we'll
有限的结果集哦，我们会
consider the linear orders on the
考虑在
outcomes on this set bell and also the
铃响的结果，以及
non strict version so social choice
非严格版本，因此是社会选择
function is going to be a function which
函数将是一个函数
maps from the set of preferences weak
偏好设置中的映射弱
preferences into outcomes so if you tell
偏好结果，所以如果你告诉
me what everybody thinks in the society
我每个人在社会上的想法
in terms of their rankings I'll pick an
根据他们的排名，我会选择一个
outcome social choice function tells you
结果社会选择功能告诉您
as a function of what people believe in
根据人们的信仰
terms of their preferences of different
他们的偏好条款不同
outcomes what's the outcome they're
结果是什么结果
going to choose a social welfare
要选择社会福利
function or a social welfare ordering is
功能或社会福利命令是
going to be the the same kind of object
将会是同一种对象
except that instead of just picking an
除了那不只是挑选一个
outcome what it's going to do is
结果它将要做的是
actually say give you a full ranking of
其实说给你一个完整的排名
outcomes so society's going to rank
结果，社会将排名
outcomes okay and that's different than
结果还可以，这与
just picking an outcome so it might be
只是选择一个结果，所以可能是
that we've got you know three outcomes
我们知道了三个结果
ABC and we ask people what the
美国广播公司，我们问人们
preferences are over these things and
偏好超过这些东西，
we're going to pick one of them so we
我们将选择其中之一，所以我们
just need to make a choice for who's
只需要选择谁
going to be our president alternatively
也要当我们的总统
we might actually want society to be
我们可能实际上希望社会成为
able to rank these objects okay so often
能够经常对这些物体进行排名
when you look at rankings of
当您查看
organizations like rankings of
喜欢的组织排名
universities or rankings of schools
大学或学校排名
we'll take a whole series of different
我们将采用一系列不同的方法
people say here's my ranking and then we
人们说这是我的排名，然后我们
aggregate those up and say okay here's
汇总这些内容，然后说还可以
an overall ranking and there might be
整体排名，可能会有
ties okay so we might have people
关系好，所以我们可能会有人
express their prayer
表达他们的祈祷
Frances or their rankings and then
Frances或他们的排名，然后
society might end up saying here's
社会可能最终会说
society's rankings okay and that's
社会的排名还可以，那就是
different so sometimes were picking an
不同，所以有时会选择
outcome sometimes we're picking a
结果有时我们会选择
ranking okay so what are some examples
排名还可以，那么有哪些例子
of these things the most basic and most
这些东西中最基本，最
widely used is what's known as plurality
广泛使用的是所谓的复数
rule
规则
what's plurality rule that's just
什么是复数规则
picking the outcome that is most
选择最重要的结果
preferred by the most people so
最受人喜欢的
everybody just gets one vote they get to
每个人都只有一票
express it and generally if we'll assume
表达它，一般来说，如果我们假设
that people are truthful we'd assume
人们会以为我们是诚实的
that they did express who's their
他们确实表达了谁是他们的
favorite and then the social welfare
最喜欢的，然后是社会福利
social choice function just picks the
社会选择功能只是选择
outcome that is most preferred by most
大多数人最喜欢的结果
people
人
so that's known as plurality rule
这就是所谓的复数规则
cumulative voting that's another
累积投票是另一回事
interesting voting rule you give people
你给人的有趣的投票规则
multiple votes so you get a set of votes
多张选票，您将获得一组选票
and you could problem you can give your
你可能会遇到问题，你可以给你
votes to different candidates so if
投票给不同的候选人，如果
there's four different candidates I can
我可以有四个不同的候选人
assign several votes to the first I can
给我可以分配的第一张票
give two to my most preferred and then
给我最喜欢的两个，然后
one each say to my second and third and
一个对我的第二个和第三个说
then we'll count up and find who has the
然后我们算起来，找出谁拥有
most votes so now I've got multiple
多数选票，所以现在我有多个
votes I can express approval voting is
我可以表示同意的投票是
another interesting voting rule and
另一个有趣的投票规则
that's one more you can basically just
那基本上可以再说一遍
express whichever outcomes you like and
表达您喜欢的结果并
not Express which ones you don't like so
不表达你不喜欢哪个
this is often used in saying electing
这通常用于说选举
new members to a club or electing new
俱乐部的新成员或选举新成员
members to a society something like that
像这样的社会成员
so you can you know like a Hall of Fame
这样你就能知道像名人堂一样
you can list which candidates you think
您可以列出您认为的候选人
should be included and then gives zeros
应该包括在内，然后给出零
basically to the ones you don't think
基本上是你不认为的
should be included so you just vote for
应该包括在内，所以您只需投票
the ones you think should be included
你认为应该包括的那些
not for the ones you don't and then
不适合那些你不想要的
there's some method of counting up and
有一些计算方法，
either picking just one if we just are
如果我们只是选一个
going to elect one candidate or picking
选一位候选人或挑选
several if we've got to pick memberships
几个，如果我们必须选择会员资格
there's some threshold and so that's
有一些门槛，所以
known as approval voting so these are
被称为批准投票，所以这些是
different methods of making choices and
不同的选择方法和
they're gonna have different properties
它们将具有不同的属性
a set of other voting voting schemes
一组其他投票表决方案
that's done on more kinds of information
在更多种类的信息上完成
ranking
排行
plurality with elimination so what's
消除后的复数是什么
known often as Instant Runoff er single
通常被称为即时径流
transferable vote or transferable voting
可转让票或可转让票
goes by a series of different names and
带有一系列不同的名称，
that in that case what one does is you
在那种情况下，你在做什么
actually express your whole preference
真正表达您的整体偏好
ordering and so you first we count
订购，所以您首先我们算一下
everybody's favorite outcome
每个人最喜欢的结果
so it's think of everybody voting for
所以想到每个人都在投票
their favorite outcome and if some
他们最喜欢的结果，如果有的话
outcome has a majority it wins so if
胜负占多数，所以如果
somebody gets more than 50% of all the
某人获得了超过50％的
votes then it wins but if nobody has a
票数，则获胜，但如果没有人
majority so if we have say three or four
多数，所以如果我们说三四个
outcomes it could be that we have some
结果可能是我们有一些
candidates that are tied or some no
并列或没有的候选人
candidate got more than a majority and
候选人获得多数票，并且
so what we do then is look at the
所以我们要做的就是看看
outcome with the fewest votes and
投票最少的结果
eliminate it okay so knock out the one
消除它好吧，所以淘汰一个
that has the fewest votes you may need a
投票最少的人，您可能需要
tiebreaking procedure to you know if
抢七程序，您是否知道
there's two that have the fewest votes
有两个选票最少的
so knock one with the fewest votes out
所以以最少的票数淘汰
and then revote so now we've only got a
然后进行投票，所以现在我们只有一个
subset of the candidates left everybody
候选人的一部分离开了所有人
expresses their favorite out of this if
表达他们的最爱，如果
somebody has a majority that's the
有人占多数
winner if not knock another one out okay
胜利者，如果不把另一个淘汰掉
and and so forth and actually there are
等等，实际上有
rules there's variations on this the you
规则有这个变化，你
know French presidential recollection
知道法国总统的回忆
works this way where you first vote and
在您第一次投票的地方以这种方式工作，
then if nobody wins enough votes in the
那么如果没有人赢得足够的选票
first round then there's a runoff among
第一轮，然后有一个径流
subset of candidates there's a number of
候选人的子集有很多
systems that work this way
以这种方式工作的系统
okay well another one is very
好吧，另一个非常
interesting and widely used what's known
有趣且用途广泛的已知信息
as border rule abort comment how do we
作为边界规则中止评论我们如何
pick outcomes under this in this case
在这种情况下选择结果
you get to give your ranking and so
你可以给出你的排名等等
you're assigning a single number to each
您正在为每个分配一个数字
outcome and so generally if I suppose I
结果，所以一般来说，如果我想我
have a ranking of I like a better than
我的排名好于
be better than C better than T if we had
如果有的话，比C比T更好
four different possible outcomes what I
四种不同的可能结果
would give is I get to give a score of
我会给一个分数
three to my preferred two to my second
第三至第二
preferred one zero and so my most
喜欢一个零，所以我最喜欢
preferred gets three votes this gets to
首选获得三票，获得
one and zero
一零
and now when we look across different
现在，当我们看到不同
individuals we add them all up right so
个人，我们将它们全部加起来，这样
somebody else has DB AC somebody else
别人有DB AC别人
has BC ad etc right so in this case D
拥有BC广告等权利，因此在这种情况下D
gets three two one zero
得到三二一零
B gets three two one zero
B得到三二一零
so B gets three votes here two votes
所以B在这里得到3票2票
here two evokes here these going to have
这里有两个唤起这些
seven votes overall and so forth so
总共7票，依此类推
board account will get numbers for each
董事会账户将获得每个数字
one of these things then we count up
这些事情之一，然后我们算
this total number of numbers and the
这个总数和
winner is the one with the most the
获胜者是最
highest score and this is actually going
最高分，这实际上正在
to produce a social welfare ordering
产生社会福利令
right it's going to tell us what's which
对，这会告诉我们这是什么
outcomes are in first place which ones
结果放在首位
are in second place and so forth it's
位居第二，依此类推
actually going to rank all the outcomes
实际上要对所有结果进行排名
and so board account gives us an overall
因此董事会帐户为我们提供了一个整体
ranking and actually this is used in a
排名，实际上这用于
lot of sports evaluations so in the US
在美国进行了很多运动评估
for ranking basketball teams or football
用于排名篮球队或橄榄球
teams and different polls and in a
团队和不同的民意调查
series of different situations where
一系列不同情况，其中
you're trying to rank alternatives you
您正在尝试对替代品进行排名
can give votes and then aggregate those
可以投票然后汇总那些
up and producer ranking another one
和生产者排名另一个
that's very interesting successive
那是非常有趣的连续
elimination you order the alternatives
消除您订购替代品
and then you first have a vote over the
然后您首先对
first two do we prefer A or B the winner
前两个是A还是B？
of that it's matched against see the
与之相对应的是
winner of that gets matched against D
的获胜者与D相匹配
the winner of that gets matched against
的赢家与
the and so forth so you order the
等等，所以您订购
alternatives do a pairwise vote and then
替代方案进行成对投票，然后
and do this this actually works often in
这样做实际上经常在
legislatures where we could imagine that
可以想象的立法机关
there was a bill introduced then
当时有一项法案
somebody amended the bill then somebody
有人修改了法案然后有人
put out an amendment to the amendment
提出修正案
and what we would do is first vote
我们要做的是首先投票
whether we do the amendment to the
我们是否对
amendment or just keep the amendment and
修改或保留修改
then the winner of that it's put up
那么它的赢家
against the bill do we want that versus
我们要账单吗
the bill and then finally we asked Bill
账单，然后我们问了比尔
no bill so that's voting by successive
没有帐单，所以要逐个表决
elimination and is often used in many
消除，经常用于许多
legislative processes so you can see
立法程序，以便您可以看到
there's many different ways of voting
有很多不同的投票方式
and choosing alternatives and these are
并选择替代品，这些是
all going to have different properties
都将具有不同的属性
and that's what makes this area so
这就是使这个区域如此
interesting
有趣
there's not a simple way to do things
没有简单的做事方法
there's many different ways to do things
有很多不同的做事方式
they're each going to have pluses and
他们每个人都有加号，
minuses and so there could be trade-offs
缺点，因此可能会取舍
involved now one important concept that
现在涉及一个重要的概念
we'll be talking about a little bit in
我们将谈论一些
the future is what's known as Condor say
未来就是所谓的神鹰说
consistency and marquis de condorcet
一致和侯爵
defined this centuries ago and the idea
定义了这个世纪前的想法
here is is looking for a candidate
这是在寻找候选人
that's preferred that beats every other
彼此击败的首选
one in a pairwise majority so if you
一个成对的多数，如果你
look you know if we've got a versus B is
看你知道我们是否有一个B
preferred to be by majority and we look
倾向于多数票，我们期待
at a versus C a is preferred to C by a
在a与C a相比C在a
majority an A to D so if a beats every
多数是A到D，所以如果每一个都击败
other alternative it has a majority of
其他替代品
votes versus all other ones then that's
选票与其他所有选票的对比
known as a Condorcet winner okay so it's
被称为Condorcet赢家好吧，所以
it's something which majority prefers to
这是大多数人都喜欢的东西
any other alternative and when those
任何其他选择以及
exist then we'll say that a rule is
存在，那么我们将说一条规则是
condors say consistent if a social
秃鹰说如果社会
choice function picks a condor say
选择功能选择神鹰说
winner when there is one okay so that's
好的，那是胜利者，那就是
a nice property that sometimes desired
有时需要的一个不错的属性
of rule and you know there can be a
规则，你知道可能会有一个
cycle so for instance if we had three
循环，例如，如果我们有三个
alternatives person one likes ABC person
一个喜欢ABC的人
two likes BCA person three likes
二喜欢BCA人三喜欢
CA B now you can see here is preferred
CA B现在您可以看到这里是首选
to be by a majority two people prefer a
占多数的两个人更喜欢
over B B's preferred to see by a
超过B B的首选
majority but C is also preferred to a by
多数，但C也优于a
a majority so we get a cycle here where
大多数，所以我们在这里得到一个循环
we end up with you know majority rule we
我们最终以您知道多数统治我们
have a beating B but be beating C and C
击败B但击败C和C
beating a so we can begin to see that
击败一个，所以我们可以开始看到
there's going to be problems with with
将会有问题
voting rules in terms of making sure
投票规则，以确保
that everything's coherent in terms of
一切都是连贯的
the way the society is gonna end up
社会的结局
making a choice and Condor say cycles
做出选择，神鹰说周期
are going to be an important part of
将成为
that it's nice if we have a Condorcet
如果我们有一个Condorcet很好
winner
优胜者
they don't always exist so the next
他们并不总是存在，所以下一个
thing we'll be talking about is is you
我们要谈论的是你
know some of the properties of voting
了解投票的一些属性
rules in more detail and then some more
规则更详细，然后更多
general results on these
这些的一般结果